(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T06:23:37.491894",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
静寂に響いてよ my howling
Echo through the silence, my howling
滔々と流れていく風景
The scenery flowing endlessly on,
刹那的な日々の中で
within these fleeting days.
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand reached out so gently,
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
a premonition of faint fever dripping in my pulse.
風に逆らう そう生きてきたから
Defying the wind, because that's how I've lived,
君に会って気付く もう独りじゃない
meeting you made me realize I'm no longer alone.
赤光 瞬きは弧描く 月へ 響く
Red light, blinking in an arc, echoing toward the moon.
爪弾く道 金狼の群れ 共に嘆く夜
The path we pluck, a pack of golden wolves, lamenting together tonight.
嗟嘆 伝播する想いは 心強く する
Sighs, propagating feelings make our hearts stronger.
着いておいでよ 後ろに君がいるから 私は迷わない 光射す道へ
Follow behind me, because you're there, so I won't hesitate toward the path of light.
無力だから 仲間を求め 凍えるから 火を灯して
Powerless, we seek companions; freezing, we light a fire,
変化とともに 進化していく この結末は 誰も知らない
Evolving alongside change, nobody knows what this ending holds.
君を信じる そう決めているから
because I've decided to believe in you.
静寂に響いてよ my howling
Resounding in the silence, my howling...
滔々と流れていく風景
Scenery flowing on torrentially,
刹那的な日々の中で
Amid fleeting days,
差し伸べられた手は優しく
The hand reached out was gentle,
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
A premonition of faint warmth dripping into my heartbeat.
風に逆らう そう生きてきたから
Going against the wind, I've lived on like this,
君に会って 気付く
Meeting you made me realize,
「もう独りじゃない」
"I'm no longer alone."
赤光 瞬きは 弧 描く 月 へ 響く
Red light, a blink tracing an arc, echoing toward the moon.
爪 弾く 道 金瞳 の 群れ 共 に 嘆く 夜
Claws flicking, a path of golden eyes, a flock lamenting together in the night.
慟哭 伝 播 する 想い は 心強く する
Wail and cry, passing on feelings, growing stronger inside.
ついて おいでよ
Come along with me,
うしろに君がいるから 私は迷わない
Because you are there beside me, I have no doubts.
光 射す 道 へ
To the path where light is cast.
無力 だから 仲間 を 求め
Powerless, I seek companions,
凍える から 火 を 灯し て
Freezing, I light a fire,
変化 とともに 進化 し てく
Progressing along with change.
この 淵源 は だれ も 知ら ない
Nobody knows this frontier.
君 を 信じる そう 決めて いる から
Because I have decided to believe in you,
どんな 異常 非常 も
Any abnormality or impossibility,
乗り越え られる よ
I can overcome.
月光 この 闇 に 唯一 凛 と 咲く 華
Moonlight, a flower uniquely and coldly blooming in this darkness.
恐れ なのか 憧れ なのか
Is it fear, or is it yearning?
向かい合う 夜空
Facing each other in the night sky.
大地 を 駆け抜け る
Running through the earth,
私 と 君 が 創り出す
You and I create this story.
この 物語 単純 な 未来 じゃ ない
It's not just a simple future.
湧き立つ 情熱 この 声 に 乗せ よう
Let this overflowing passion ride on this voice.
空 飛ぶ 羽根 なく て も
Even without wings to fly through the skies,
手 は 繋げ られ た から
Our hands were able to clasp.
この 運命 を 選ん だ
I chose this destiny.
連動 する 遠吠え は 静寂 に 響い て
Distant howlings chain together, echoing in the silence,
何度も何度もその絆を確かめ合った
Confirming that bond again and again.
瞬きは弧描き月へ響く
Blinks trace an arc, echoing toward the moon.
爪弾く道金瞳の群れ共に嘆く夜
Claws flicking, a path of golden eyes, a flock lamenting together in the night.
慟哭伝播する想いは心強くする
Wail and cry, passing on feelings, growing stronger inside.
ともに行こうよ
Let's go together,
となりに君がいるから
Because you are there,
私は迷わない
I have no doubts.
光射す道へ
To the path where light is cast.
listen to my howling...!
狼が止まることはない
A wolf will never stop howling.
というわけで、1曲目はHowlingでしたー！
And that's it, the first song was Howling!
大神ミオ4周年記念ライブ「Mio Forest Night Party」に来てくれてありがとう！嬉しいよー！
Thank you for coming to Okami Mio's 4th Anniversary Live, "Mio Forest Night Party"! I'm so happy!
えーっとですね、今回、えーこちらのね、えータグなんですけれども、大神ミオ4周年記念ということで、ぜひこちらのタグでつぶやいてくれるとすごく嬉しいです！スクショもいっぱい撮ってね！
And now, about the tag for today... Since it's Okami Mio's 4th Anniversary, I'd be super happy if you tweeted using this tag! Please take lots of screenshots too!
ってわけでね、あの、今回ね、ライブステージ、なんかいい感じに星がいっぱい付いてるなと思ったんですけど、こちらのステージと、あとこちらのロゴですね！
So, for this live stage, I thought the stage vibe was really nice. This stage and the logo...
こちらを、えーいつもお世話になっております、作成者様にお願いいたしまして、デザインありがとうございましたー！
I asked the creator who always helps me to design them. Thank you so much for the design!
あ、ちょっと引きで撮ってくれてる！すごい可愛いんだよ、このデザインが。いっぱい星が流れてるしね。
Oh, they're capturing it on video too! It's so cute, with all these stars floating around.
というわけでね、えー、まあ、いっぱいお祝いしてもらいまして、えー、まだまだ始まったうちのライブなんですけれどもちまったばかりのね、えー、ゲストの方も来てくれているらしい！
So, um, we're celebrating a lot, and our live just started, but we also have guest performers coming!
誰なんだいったい！ということで、最後まで楽しんでいってねみんな！
Who on earth is it?! So, enjoy yourselves until the very end, everyone!
あ、なんか次の曲の準備しなきゃいけないみたい。じゃ、ちょっと行ってくるね！行ってきまーす！
Oh, it looks like I need to get ready for the next song. So, I'll go and come back!
仮面越し今日も見えている いつもと変わらない笑顔
Hiding behind a mask again today, a smile that's no different from usual.
纏う それは仮面か
What I wear is a mask.
本当の自分を教えて 気飾り澄まし顔じゃなく
Instead of showing my true self and acting tough with a feigned composure,
呆れるほど 臆病ならば
There's cowardice enough to make me want to give up.
いつわりは it's all the same
Even if it's a pretense, it's all the same.
真実は open my heart
The truth is open my heart.
君に全てを吹っ切って走れ 加速していく 世界で生きてこう
I'll shake off everything to you and accelerate, living on through the world.
遠くから聞き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
Far away, I'm getting tired of hearing it.
一風の風で決められた運命ならば抗うよ
If it's a destiny decided by a sudden gust of wind, I'll defy it.
見つけるよ 奥にある理由
I'll find the reason that lies deep within.
可愛いだけじゃもういられない声を上げていくんだ stardust song
Just being cute isn't enough, I'll raise my voice in a stardust song!
臆病の自分へ
A timid self...
足元見るだけで精一杯
Just looking at my feet is all I can do,
道を探してるような僕には
for someone like me searching for a path.
君に触れることはできるのかな
Can I really reach out and touch you?
My please me answer
簡単な feeling myself
Simple feeling myself,
君と恋をする心のまま飛び出せ
jump out with a heart falling in love with you!
加速していく 世界で生きていく僕らの
Accelerating, living in this world,
道のほうへ 歩くことはやめない
we won't stop walking down our own path.
一か八かの 賭けだったとしても構わない
Even if it's a double-or-nothing bet, I don't care.
立ち向かい 行くよ 痛みを増すそのために
I'll face forward and go, just to increase the pain.
眩いスターダスト 夜空にもう一度
Dazzling stardust, once more into the night sky,
汗だくに付加価値を 僕らでもう一度
adding value to our sweat, once more together,
眩いスターダスト 夜空にもう一度
Dazzling stardust, once more into the night sky,
声は確かに変わる
my voice surely changes.
アポロさん もう迷うことはない
Apollo-san, I won't get lost anymore.
僕だけの道標 胸に刻んで
Carving my own signpost into my chest,
加速していく 世界で生きていく僕ら
accelerating, living in this world,
聴き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
I'm sick of hearing those comparing voices.
一かゼロの風 決められた運命ならば
If it's a fate decided by binary winds,
逆らうよ 見つけるよ 僕である理由
I'll defy it, I'll find my reason for being me.
いつでも僕らしくありたい
I always want to be true to myself,
今を輝くんだスターダスト
shining in the present, stardust!
可愛いだけじゃもういられない
I can't just be cute anymore,
声を上げていくんだスターダスト
I'll raise my voice, stardust!
どうだっていいことを 嘘って吐いて戻れない
Spitting lies about things that don't matter, I can't turn back.
事故なんてやってこない 奪われたように奪われて
Accidents never come, having things taken away as if robbed.
今日だって叶わない 思ったように騙せない
Even today doesn't come true, I can't deceive as I hoped.
クソ喰い生いる僕には クソッタレものじゃ分からない
For someone like me eating crap, I can't understand such bullshit.
おいね ここまで
Hey, up to here,
捨てて隠してしまったんだ
I threw it away and hid it.
命題の答え分かっても もう締め付けなくていいんだよ
Even if I know the answer, I don't have to strangle myself anymore.
栄誉で僕が分かったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな セイ
If I'm understood with glory, will you smile at me once more? Say!
名も知らず白んで
Whitening without knowing my name,
嘘つきだって知るんだよね
you know I'm a liar, right?
野良犬と言うはずが 狂ってSOS心に出すよ
Calling me a stray dog, I go crazy and send out an SOS.
後悔の惰弱は 手離した方が正義なの？
Is it more righteous to let go of regret's weakness?
臆病だって構わない 祈っておいてそれは無い
I don't care if I'm cowardly, praying and then doing that is wrong.
飾っていた上達が ボケっと追って呆れるたば
The progress I flaunted leaves me blank and dumbfounded.
おいね どこまで
Hey, how far
惹き殺しゃしたって
will you drag me down and kill me?
目で僕を叱ってよ 正直者だよでみたいなら
Scold me with your eyes, if you want to see an honest person.
ヘイ 目で僕を裁いてよ 最後まで甘えてしまうのは
Hey, judge me with your eyes, ending up spoiling until the very end...
暴れ出すんだよ
is going wild!
食い荒らして知るんだよな
Knowing as I devour everything,
嘘つきだって知るんだよね
you know I'm a liar, right?
足りないものは望んだら 僕じゃない僕に出会ったよ
If I wished for what I lacked, I met a me that wasn't me.
それでも前進んだの 暗々くらしちゃうような
Still, I kept moving forward, even if it gets pitch dark.
足りない僕を愛してよ
Love the me that's not enough,
親のままが僕を育てたの 君には僕が見えるかな
the way my parents raised me—can you see me?
マリオネットと分かっても
Even if you know you're a marionette,
もう抱きしめなくっていいんだよ
you don't need to hug me anymore.
ねえ、僕が分かったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな
Hey, if you understand me, will you smile for me once more?
ねえ、僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢みたいなら
Hey, scold me, if being honest is like a dream.
ねえ、僕をさばいてよ 最後まで愛してしまうのは
Hey, judge me, because loving until the very end...
ねえ、僕を愛してよ もうすぐ終わるこの世界から
Hey, love me, from this world that is ending soon.
ねえ、僕と踊ってよ 最初からいだいとわかってた
Hey, dance with me, I knew it hurt from the beginning.
幻だって知るんだよ
I know it's an illusion.
嘘つきだって知るんだよ
I know you're a liar.
棒読みだって知るんだよ
I know it's a deadpan reading.
空白だって知るんだよ
I know it's blank.
戸惑っていいことを 嘘って吐いても戻れない
Even if you lie about being confused, you can't go back.
自己だってやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
Accidents don't happen, taken away as if stolen.
目覚めて始まる 朝の定め
Awakening, the destiny of morning begins.
麗しく尊いままの意志疎通を
With communication as graceful and precious as ever.
無意味な小節 万客往来
Meaningless verses, crowds coming and going,
稀有の見込み
and rare prospects.
移ろいかぞえ しめやかな情動
Counting fleeting changes, quiet emotions,
寝不足にすり替えた気懸り
and anxiety disguised as lack of sleep.
ひしゃげた顔を突き潰されて 張り付けられた顔が
My squashed face smashed in, a pasted-on face
日々割れてゆく 渾然一体までつぐんだこの輪廻返しては
Cracking day by day, returning this sealed reincarnation.
刻まれた実は すり減り続く
The carved fruit continues to wear down.
ああ、答えを 至上主義アドトラックで白昼夢中を駆け回る
Ah, racing through daytime daydreams in a supreme ad truck.
所詮使い捨ての消耗品だっと っと息気にならないや
After all, it's disposable, so I don't care at all.
バスト突き上げてやれ夜を飲み込む星の花
Blast it open and swallow the night, star flowers!
また其処に耳が重ねられていく祈り丸めて投げ放つ
Prayers are piled upon ears again, rolled up and thrown away.
最後一本の包帯 今日もそう
The last bandage, today as well,
黎明の突き刺した狭間
the gap pierced by dawn.
行き詰まる下がり天井 窮屈の黒格子
A dead-end lowered ceiling, cramped black lattice.
恵みにも負け 続き風にも負け
Defeated by blessings, defeated by continuous winds,
錆び付いて動く 食指の定則
the rusted and moving rules of index fingers.
慎まし増した車輪 巻き返したいのさ
Wheels that have grown modest, I want to turn them back.
命短し恋せよ乙女 ルールに逆らっては
Maidens, fall in love, life is short! Defying the rules,
弾かれた枠 擦り抜ける古い
slipping through the repelled frame of the old.
ああ、答えを 至上主義アドトラックで四六時中を駆け回る
Ah, racing around the clock in a supreme ad truck.
所詮使い捨ての消耗品だっと っと息気にならないや
After all, it's disposable, so I don't care at all.
ぶち上げてやれ夜を飲み込む星の花
Blast it open and swallow the night, star flowers!
また一つ指で押し開けていく祈り横へと滑らせる
Pushing open one finger at a time, sliding prayers aside.
平静したままの 感情セーブが
Calm emotional restraint...
流されたりそう 星の苦言
swept away, perhaps? Bitter words of the stars.
実の現実 ああ、答えを
The actual reality... Ah, the answer:
至上主義アドトラックで四六時中を駆け回る
Racing around the clock in a supreme ad truck.
所詮使い捨ての消耗品だっと っと息気にならないや
After all, it's disposable, so I don't care at all.
ぶち上げてやれ夜を飲み込む星の花
Blast it open and swallow the night, star flowers!
所詮二つ目の太陽を 縫いつけていこうパス
Sewing on the second sun, let's keep going.
仕掛けてやれば夜に佇む星の花 また空に導かれていく祈り求め
Star flowers lingering in the night, guided once more into the skies.
深愛
[Song: Shin'ai]
雪が舞い散る夜空
The snowy night sky where snow dances down,
ふたり寄り添い見上げた
the two of us looked up, leaning close together.
つながる手と手の温もりは
The warmth of our connected hands
とても優しかった
was so tender.
淡いオールドブルーの
Fading away into the clouds
雲間に消えていくでしょう
of pale old blue...
永遠へと続くはずの
That promise that was supposed to last for eternity,
あの約束
that promise...
あなたの傍にいるだけで
Just being by your side,
ただそれだけでよかった
just that alone was enough.
いつの間に膨らむ
Before I knew it, my dreams grew
現実以上の夢に気付かずに
beyond reality without me realizing.
どんな時もどこにいる時でも
No matter when, no matter where I am,
強く強く抱きしめていて
hold me tight, hold me close.
情熱が日常に染まるとしても
Even if passion fades into everyday life,
あなたへのこの想いはすべて
all these feelings for you
終わりなどないと信じている
I believe will never end.
あなただけずっと見つめているの
I've always been gazing at just you.
交わす言葉と時間
The words we exchanged and the time we shared,
姿を変えていくでしょう
changing their form...
白い頬に解けたそれは
Melting on my white cheeks,
月の涙
those are the tears of the moon.
「行かないで、もう少しだけ」
"Don't go, just a little longer,"
何度も言いかけては
I tried saying over and over,
「また会えるよね？きっと」
"We'll meet again, right? Surely,"
何度も自分に問いかける
I asked myself repeatedly.
突然走り出した行く先の
Suddenly running off to different futures,
違う二人もう止まらない
the two of us can no longer stop.
沈黙が想像を超え引き裂いて
Silence tears through beyond imagination,
一つだけ許される願いがあるなら
if there is only one wish allowed,
「ごめんね」と伝えたい
I want to say "I'm sorry."
いくら想っていても届かない
No matter how much I think of you, it won't reach,
声にしないと動き出さない
unless I give it voice, it won't move.
隠したままの二人の秘密
Our secret left hidden away—
このまま忘れられてしまうの？
will it just be forgotten like this?
だから…ねえ、早く今ココに来て
So hey... hurry and come here now.
あなたの傍にいるだけで
Just being by your side,
ただそれだけでよかった
just that alone was enough.
今度めぐり会えたらもっともっと笑い合えるかな…
If we meet again this time, can we laugh together even more...?
どんな時もどこにいる時でも
No matter when, no matter where you are,
強く強く抱きしめていて
hold me tight, hold me close.
情熱よりアツイ体温で溶かして
Melt me with a body heat hotter than passion,
あなたへのこの想いはすべて
all these feelings for you
終わりなどないと信じている
I believe will never end.
あなただけずっと見つめているの
I've always been gazing at just you.
あなたの傍にいるだけで
Just being by your side,
ただそれだけでよかった
just that alone was enough.
こんどめぐり会えたら
If we meet again this time,
もっともっと笑い合えるかな
can we laugh together even more?
どんな時もどこにいる時でも
No matter when, no matter where you are,
強く強く抱きしめていて
hold me tight, hold me close.
情熱より熱い熱で確かめて
Confirm it with a heat even more intense than passion,
あなたへのこの想いはすべて
all these feelings for you
終わりなどないと信じている
I believe will never end.
あなただけずっと見つめているの
I've always been gazing at just you.
はい、ということで
So, with that,
四曲連続でお送りしましたー！わあーー！
we've delivered four songs in a row! Yayyy!
え、今回は、えーっとね、親愛リベンジできたんじゃないかと思うんですけど
Um, this time, I think we managed to get our revenge, you know?
どう、どう、どうですか？親愛、あの、二年前のことを覚えてますみんな、あの、ちょっとケーキがやばかった時の、あ
How, how, how is it? Dear, um, do you all remember two years ago, when the cake was crazy, um—
ああー！で、できてた！あ、よかったよかった！できてたみたいです。よかったよかった、いぇーい！
Ah! It worked out! Ah, good, good! It seemed to work out. Good, good, yay!
というわけで、え、今回ゲストに、え、フレア、わため、そしてかなたん、あずちゃん、ルイ姉に来てもらいました！ありがとうー！
So, um, this time as guests, we had Flare, Watame, Kanatan, Azu-chan, and Lui-nee come join us! Thank you so much!
ちょっとね、あの、うちが歌ってみたいなっていうふうに思った
Um, I asked the members I wanted to sing with
メンバーに、ええ、オファーをかけさせてもらいまして、そのメンバーに合わないかなっていう曲を独断と偏見で選ばせてもらいました！
to join, and I chose songs for them based on my own arbitrary bias!
一緒に歌ってめちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！ありがとうございました！
Singing together was so much fun! Thank you so much!
というわけで、ええ、すごいね、最高のステージを作れたなと思うんですけど、
So, um, I think we've made an amazing, top-notch stage,
ここからもね、まだまだあるのでね、皆さんお楽しみしていただければと思います！楽しみだな、うちも楽しみなんだよねー！
but there's still more to come, so I hope you all look forward to it! I'm so excited, I'm looking forward to it too!
で、なんと次が！新ステージがあるみたいな、噂なんですが、おや、や、や？
And guess what? Next, there's a rumor that there's a new stage! Oh, oh, oh?
そろそろ準備もできたみたいなので、で！うちも行ってきまーす！みんなも一緒に会場に移動しようー！
It looks like preparations are ready, so! I'm going too! Let's all move to the venue together!
おい、トランクを上に乗せたまま動いちゃだめだよー！
Hey, you mustn't move with the trunk on top!
僕が生まれる前よりも
Before I was even born,
ずっと昔から続くように
as if continuing from long ago,
そういつも傷付け合ってまた愛し合うのさ
we always hurt each other and love each other again.
結婚や仕事のトークにまた ちょっと疲れてたとしても
Even if you're a bit tired of wedding and work talks,
そう僕も他人事なんじゃない、わかってるのさ
I know it's not somebody else's problem for me either.
明けない夜はないと
There is no night that doesn't end,
夜明け前がただ暗いと
just that right before dawn is dark.
この先に待つ明日が そんなに輝くもんかな?
Could tomorrow waiting ahead really shine so brightly?
今 I LOVE YOU で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, illuminate us starting with an "I love you" even more!
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You って諦めモードでも wow 飛び跳ねて行けよ
Look, even in a "I miss you" give-up mood, wow, go bouncing along!
時代柄暗い話題が流行りだけど、愛を謳う
Dark topics are trendy nowadays, but sing of love.
自分が取るに足らぬ事で いつも悩んだりしているのは
Always worrying over things of little worth,
言っちゃえばアダムとイブから もう決まってたのさ
truth be told, was decided way back from Adam and Eve.
なんとなく恋に落ちて いつの間にか本気だって
Falling in love somehow, before noticing, being dead serious—
張り裂けそうな胸の奥を 打ち明けなくちゃくんなくちゃ
I've got to pour out the depths of my bursting chest!
今 I LOVE YOU で始まる僕らを もっと満たしてくれよ
Now, fulfill us starting with an "I love you" even more!
イメージ通りには運ばぬ物としても まだ信じてみたいのさ
Even if things don't go as imagined, I still want to believe.
ほら I Miss You って賞味期限がある Oh Yes 急かしてくれよ
Look, "I miss you" has an expiration date, Oh Yes, hurry me along!
時代柄暗い未来が待ち受けど、愛を謳う
A dark future awaits us in these times, but sing of love.
ああどうか夜明けまで 君の声が聞きたい
Ah, please, until dawn, I want to hear your voice.
いつどの時代も変わり映えしなくてさ
No matter the era, it never changes much,
僕ら同じ目で悩んだり、悲しんだり、笑ったりしてんのにさ
yet we worry, grieve, and laugh with the same eyes.
解り合うのはそう簡単じゃない ただこんなにも君とリンクしてる、重なっていく
Understanding each other isn't that simple, yet we're linked with each other so much, overlapping.
今 I LOVE YOU で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, illuminate us starting with an "I love you" even more!
変わらない愛や希望の類も まだ信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in unchanging love and hope.
ほら I Miss You って諦めモードでも wow 飛び跳ねて行けよ
Look, even in a "I miss you" give-up mood, wow, go bouncing along!
時代柄暗い話題が流行りだけど、愛を謳う
Dark topics are trendy nowadays, but sing of love.
僕が生まれる前よりも ずっと昔から続くように
Before I was even born, as if continuing from long ago,
そういつも傷付け合ってまた愛し合うのさ
we always hurt each other and love each other again.
僕が生まれる前よりも ずっとながら続くように
Even before I was born, as if continuing from way back when,
そういつもしっかり合って また愛し合うのさ
yes, always hurting and loving each other once more.
結婚や仕事のトークにまた ちょっと 疲れていたとしても
Even if you're a bit tired from talks of marriage and work,
そう僕も他人事なんかじゃない、 わかってるのさ
yes, I know it's not someone else's problem either.
ほら I Miss Youって諦めモードでも wow 駆け抜けて行けよ
Hey, even in a give-up mode saying "I Miss You", wow, run right through it!
時代柄暗い話題が街行くけれど、 愛を謳う
Though gloomy topics of the times fill the streets, sing of love.
僕が取るに足らぬ事で いつも悩んだりしているのは
That I'm always worrying over trivial things—
言っちまえばアダムとイブから もう決まってたのさ
truth be told, it was already decided since Adam and Eve.
なんとなく 恋に落ちて いつの間にか本気だって
Somehow falling in love, before I knew it, I was dead serious;
張り裂けそうな胸の奥を 打ち明けなくっちゃな
I've got to pour out the depths of my bursting heart.
今 I Love Youで始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれないか
Illuminate us more, we who begin with "I Love You";
変わりない愛や希望の類も まだ 信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in unchanging love and hope.
キラリと流れてる 見つけて欲しいから、ここにいるの
Streaming with a flash—since I want you to find me, I'm right here.
誰かが手を伸ばす合図で そっとまわる星青く 光って
At the signal of someone stretching out their hand, the slowly spinning heavenly body shines in blue.
初めての冬がきたよ 誰もいない公園で 星がぶつかる音に胸が鳴る
The first winter has come to the empty park, my heart pounds with the sound of stars colliding.
ブランコから見上げた空 名前はわからないけれど 近づきたいよほうき星になって
The sky I looked up at from the swing—though I don't know its name, I want to get close, becoming a comet.
初めての冬がきたよ 誰もいない公園で
The first winter has come to the empty park,
星がぶつかる音に胸が鳴る
my heart pounds with the sound of stars colliding.
ブランコから見上げた空 名前はわからないけれど
The sky I looked up at from the swing—though I don't know its name,
近づきたいよほうき星になって
I want to get close, becoming a comet.
キラリと走る光 みんなが指さして笑っていた
The light running with a flash—everyone was pointing and smiling.
君が私を呼んでるのだろう？ もっとつなぐ力にして 届いて
Are you calling for me? Put more power into connecting, and reach me!
わた雲が消えていくのか 風が運んでいた
The fleecy clouds are vanishing—the wind was carrying them.
夜の闇に私の姿映る
My form reflects in the dark of the night.
最近は街あかりで 星を忘れてしまう人
People who flat out forget about the stars because of street lights these days,
これがもう最後だから 見ていてね
since this is now the end, be watching, okay?
キラリと流れてる 見つけて欲しいから、ここにいるの
Streaming with a flash—since I want you to find me, I'm right here.
誰かが手を伸ばす合図で そっとまわる星青く 光って
At the signal of someone stretching out their hand, the slowly spinning heavenly body shines in blue.
キラリと走る星は 思い出すのさ、遊んでいたあの空
I remember the heavenly body that runs with a flash, that sky where we were playing.
はじけて消えていく光の軌跡 また会おうね、この空で きっと
The tracks of the light that's popping and vanishing—we'll meet again, okay, in this sky, surely.
キラリと流れてる 見つけたいから ここにいるの
A shooting star drifting across the sky, wanting to be found here.
誰かが手を伸ばす合図で そっとまわる星 青く光って
As someone reaches out their hand, the stars spin softly, glowing blue.
光って
Shining brightly...
キナリと走る星は 思い出して遊んでいたあの空
Like a shooting star running across the sky, reminding me of the skies we played in.
はじけて消えていく光の軌跡
The trail of light bursting and fading away.
また会おうね、この空で
Let's meet again in this sky.
きっと
For sure...
きっと...
...For sure.
鬼灯日和
[Song: Hozuki Biyori]
沈む茜日
The setting crimson sun,
染まる坂道
dyeing the slopes,
歌う雫に
to the singing droplets,
懐かしさにじむ
oozing with nostalgia.
夜の帳の 近づく音に
As night's curtain draws near,
はしゃいだ君の声一つ空に響いた
your excited voice echoed alone into the sky.
稲荷の前で待ち合わせ 吊られた鳥居潜り抜け
Meeting in front of Inari shrine, slipping past hanging torii gates,
小さな淡い影
a small, faint shadow
胸をすり抜けてく
slipping through my chest.
踊れ踊れ 手を組んで
Dance, dance, joining hands,
夜更かしした僕らは
we who stayed up late,
身動きも忘れて
forgetting how to move,
燈すのは灯り、ひらひら
lighting up lights, fluttering,
踊れ踊れ 手を組んで
Dance, dance, joining hands,
妖気したほうへと
toward the eerie vibe,
鳴り響く大鼓の音に
to the resounding taiko beat,
赤い火がジグザグと
red flames zig-zagging,
君に気づけたかな
did I notice you?
響くざわめき
Resounding commotion,
燃ゆるかがり火
burning bonfires,
揺らぐ気持ちに
swaying feelings,
思い出せよう
let's recall.
祭りばやしが 届く音に
To the sound of festival music reaching us,
天の川の雲が暮れ胸を突いた
Milky Way clouds grew dark and pierced my chest.
今宵空にはおぼろ月 かすんだ心ごまかした
Tonight's hazy moon disguised my clouded heart.
下駄の音がカチカチ鳴って
The sound of geta clacking away,
胸をすり抜けたら
slipping through my chest,
目を閉じて巡れ巡れ意識をとざい
Closing eyes, spinning, shutting off consciousness,
人よ人に募る嘘を月明かり照らす花火
fireworks illuminating lies between people under moonlight.
自らはらはら泣いて泣いて流るる雫 嫁入り前のさよしぐれ
Crying, streaming droplets, a fleeting shower before a bride's departure.
傘の外 聞くねびよりに
Outside the umbrella, hearing the sleeping weather,
宵のしぐれ隠した 君に気づけたような気がした
hiding the evening shower, it felt like I noticed you.
沈む茜染まる坂道
The sloping road dyed in setting sun's madder red...
伝う霙に切なさ滲む
Sadness bleeds into the flowing sleet.
夜の帳の近付く音に
To the sound of night's curtain approaching,
はしゃいだキミの声ひとつ 空に響いていた
your excited voice echoed alone in the sky.
稲荷の前で待ち合わせ
Meeting up in front of the Inari shrine,
連なる鳥居くぐり抜け
passing through the rows of torii gates,
鬼灯の甘い風 胸をすり抜けていった
the sweet breeze of Chinese lantern plants slipped through our chests.
「踊ろうよ」
“Let's dance,”
廻れ廻れ手を叩いてほら 見様見真似で輪になって
spin, spin, clap your hands, imitating each other to form a circle,
ぎこちない振り付けに舞う 袖はひらひら
dancing with clumsy choreography, sleeves fluttering.
踊れ踊れ手を取り合って 上気した頬牡丹色
Dance, dance, holding hands, flushed cheeks peony-colored,
鳴り響く太鼓の音に 赤い果実弾けた
to the resonating sound of drums, red fruits burst open.
キミに気付かれたかな？
Did you notice me, I wonder?
響くざわめき燃ゆる狐火
Resonating commotion, burning foxfire.
まだこの世界は 僕を飼い馴らしていたいみたいだ
It seems like this world still wants to keep on taming me,
望み通りいいだろう 美しくもがくよ
just as it wishes, right? I'll beautifully struggle against it.
互いの砂時計 眺めながらキスをしようよ
Let's kiss while gazing at each other's hourglasses.
「さよなら」から一番 遠い 場所で待ち合わせしよう
Let's meet up in the place farthest from "goodbye."
辞書にある言葉で 出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world built up with words in a dictionary.
万華鏡の中で 八月のある朝
Inside a kaleidoscope, on a certain morning in August,
君は僕の前で 恥ずかしそうに澄ましみせた
you acted all bashful and composed in front of me.
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で
With a smile like the textbook of this world.
ついに時はきた 昨日までは序章の序章で
The time has finally come—until yesterday was the prologue to the prologue.
飛ばし読みでいいから ここからが僕だよ
You can skim it, but my main chapter starts right here.
経験と知識と カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
Armed with experience, knowledge, and courage growing a bit of mold,
いまだかつてない スピードで君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive to your side at a speed never seen before.
まどろみの中で 生生しいコーラに
Over lukewarm cola in a drowsy haze,
夢見たよ
I dreamed a dream.
教室の窓の外に 電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
Outside the classroom window, on a morning carried along, rocked by a train,
愛し方さえも 君の匂いがした
even the way to love smelled like you.
歩き方さえも その笑い声がした
Even the way of walking carried the sound of your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる君のすべてを この目に焼き付けておくことは もう権利なんかじゃない 義務だと思うんだ
Burning every part of you that will eventually vanish into my eyes—I believe that is no longer a right, but my duty.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
No matter how far words like "fate" or "future" reach out, we fall in love in a place they cannot touch.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
The hands of the clock advance while taking a side glance at us.
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも 生き抜いていこう
In such a world, let's live through it together for a lifetime—no, for any number of chapters.
まだこの世界は 僕を飼い馴らしていたいみたいだ
It seems like this world still wants to keep on taming me,
望み通りいいだろう 美しくもがくよ
just as it wishes, right? I'll beautifully struggle against it.
互いの砂時計 眺めながらキスをしようよ
Let's kiss while gazing at each other's hourglasses.
「さよなら」から一番 遠い 場所で待ち合わせしよう
Let's meet up in the place farthest from "goodbye."
辞書にある言葉で 出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world built up with words in a dictionary.
万華鏡の中で 八月のある朝
Inside a kaleidoscope, on a certain morning in August,
君は僕の前で 恥ずかしそうに澄ましみせた
you acted all bashful and composed in front of me.
この世界の教科書のような笑顔で
With a smile like the textbook of this world.
ついに時はきた 昨日までは序章の序章で
The time has finally come—until yesterday was the prologue to the prologue.
飛ばし読みでいいから ここからが僕だよ
You can skim it, but my main chapter starts right here.
経験と知識と カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
Armed with experience, knowledge, and courage growing a bit of mold,
いまだかつてない スピードで君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive to your side at a speed never seen before.
まどろみの中で 生生しいコーラに 夢見たよ
Over lukewarm cola in a drowsy haze, I dreamed a dream.
教室の窓の外に 電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
Outside the classroom window, on a morning carried along, rocked by a train,
愛し方さえも 君の匂いがした
even the way to love smelled like you.
歩き方さえも その笑い声がした
Even the way of walking carried the sound of your laughter.
まだこの世界は 僕を飼い馴らしていたみたいだ
Still, this world seems to want to keep on taming me.
望み通りいいだろう 美しくもがくよ
Just as you wish, right? I'll beautifully struggle against it.
互いの砂時計 眺めながらキスをしようよ
Let's kiss, watching each other's hourglasses.
「さよなら」から一番 遠い 場所で待ち合わせよう
Let's meet up far away from "goodbye."
ついに時はきた 昨日までは序章の序章で
The time has finally come over the prologue until yesterday.
飛ばし読みでいいから ここからが僕だよ
You can skip it, as my main chapter starts from here.
経験と知識と カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
Drawing on experience, knowledge, and mildewy courage,
今だかつてないスピードで 君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive to you at a speed higher than ever before.
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
Over lukewarm cola in a drowsy state,
ここではないどこかを 夢見たよ
I dreamed of somewhere different from here.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window,
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
or on a train in the morning.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how far the words like "fate" or "future" reach for,
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we'll fall in love in a place where they can't get at.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
The clock hands proceed, taking a side glance at us.
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも
In such a world, throughout our lifetime, no, in any number of chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's live on together.
愛し方さえも 君の匂いがした
Even the way of loving was scented with you.
歩き方さえも その笑い声がした
Even the way of walking carried the voice of your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる 君のすべてを
All of you that would vanish eventually,
この目に焼き付けておくことは
to burn it into my memory—
もう権利なんかじゃない 義務だと思うんだ
now it is, I believe, more my duty than my right.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how far the words like "fate" or "future" reach for,
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we'll fall in love in a place where they can't get at.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
The clock hands proceed, taking a side glance at us.
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも
In such a world, throughout our lifetime, no, in any number of chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's live on together.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how far the words like "fate" or "future" reach for,
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we'll fall in love in a place where they can't get at.
時計の針も二人を 横目に見ながら進む
The clock hands proceed, taking a side glance at us.
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも
In such a world, throughout our lifetime, no, in any number of chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's live on together.
運命だとか未来とかって 言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how far the words like "fate" or "future" reach for,
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で僕ら恋をする
we'll fall in love in a place where they can't get at.
そんな世界を二人で 一生 いや、何章でも
In such a world, throughout our lifetime, no, in any number of chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's live on together.
というわけでスパークルでした！
And that was "Sparkle"!
いい曲だよね。
Such a great song, right?
初めて歌ってみたということで、とても思い出深い曲です。ありがとうございました。
It's the first time I've ever sung it as a cover, so it's a very memorable song. Thank you so much!
というわけで、4曲一気にお送りさせてもらいました！
So, I've just delivered four songs all at once!
そして、新ステージだ！わーい！
And look, a new stage! Yay!
かわいい！
It's so cute!
まずは、ちょっとゲストに来てもらったので、ゲストの皆さんをご紹介しましょう。
First off, since we had some guests join us, let me introduce them.
こよ、風病、そしてあやめにきてもらいましたわー！ありがとう！めちゃ可愛かった！
Koyori, Fubuki, and Ayame came along! Yay! Thank you! They were so cute!
みんな頑張ってね、あの
Everyone worked so hard,
サイリウムではなく自分が揺れることでね
cheering us on not as Cyrium,
応援してくれてますね、カバハイ！
thank you so much!
けど後ろから見ると、なんか灰色の草が揺れてるみたいだな。
Though from behind, it looks like gray grass swaying.
すっごい可愛い。
So cute!
ちょっと後でね、毛布ったりとかしたいんですけれども、君たち立体化したんだねえ！
You guys really became 3D!
はい、というわけでちょっと
Well then...
新しいものが多すぎて、なんか全然追いつかないんですけれども
There are too many new things, I can't quite keep up,
まあ、いっぱい用意してくれた運営さん本当にありがとうございました！
but thank you so much to the management team for preparing so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
さて、え、まだまだちょっとライブは続くんですが
Now then, the live stream is still continuing,
次にちょっとそろそろ行こうかなと思います。
I think it's about time to move on to the next part.
なんかみんな気づいてる？あの、ついこないだうちオリジナル曲出したよね。
Did you guys notice that we released an original song the other day?
それまだ聴いてないなって思うよね。
I'm sure you're thinking, "I haven't listened to it yet!"
うんうん、ちょっと準備してくるから。
I'll get it ready for you, so...
じゃあ、ちょっと準備してきますね。みんな楽しみにしててね、最後まで絶対見てね！行ってきまーす！
So everyone, look forward to it and make sure to watch until the very end! Here we go!
ネオンライトは眩く
Neon lights are dazzling
街灯明滅 通り過ぎ
Streetlights flicker as I pass by
窓の向こう 夜の風に 空を見た
Looking up at the sky in the night wind beyond the window
忙しない足取り
With no time to even catch my breath,
まばらなノイズ
Amidst a scattered noise,
私だけが 取り残されたようで
It felt like I was the only one left behind.
ゆめうつつ また光に揺られる
Caught in a daydream, swaying in the light once again
心の中で私を消して
Erase me from inside your heart...
追いかけた過去 背中合わせの
The past I chased, back-to-back with
希望 密度 押しつぶされないよう
Hope and density, trying not to crush me.
だから君と ここにいる時間は
That's why, when I'm here with you,
言葉にできず 見つめ合うだけ
Without words, we just gaze at each other.
思考回路 ぼやけたままで さあ 光を掴むまで
My thoughts are still blurred, so come on, until I grasp the light.
サヨナラは、まだ
Sayonara is still...
暗いカーテン 向こうの
Beyond the dark curtains,
偏光反射 籠の鳥
Polarized reflection, a bird in a cage.
閉じたい心 隠したくて
Hiding a closed heart,
ふと一人 また光に溺れる
All alone, I sink into the light once again.
呼吸する暇もなくて 沈む
With not even a moment to breathe, I sink.
時の狭間で 隣り合わせの
In the gaps of time, side by side,
理想 現実 押しつぶされないよ
Ideal and reality, trying not to crush me.
だから私 繋がっていたいの
That's why I want to stay connected.
見つめ合うたび 微笑み合って
Every time we meet eyes, we smile at each other,
だけど君は ぼやけたままでさ
yet you remain blurred.
巡り すれ違って 惹かれ合う また
Passing each other by, we are drawn together once more.
(Endless Night, Endless Light)
(Inner the Cage, Outside the Cage)
逃げ出してみたい
I want to try escaping.
(This story will end, though)
心 離れずに溺れ… 未来に魅入られる
Without parting, sinking... fascinated by the future.
夢の中なら私と きっと
In a dream, surely with you...
追いかけた過去 背中合わせの
The past I chased, back-to-back with
希望 密度 押しつぶされないよ
Hope and density, trying not to crush me.
だから君と ここにいる時間は
That's why, when I'm here with you,
言葉にできず 見つめ合うだけ
without words, we just gaze at each other.
思考回路 ぼやけたままで さあ 光を掴むまで
My thoughts are still blurred, so come on, until I grasp the light.
サヨナラは、まだ
Sayonara is still...
聴こえますか
Can you hear me?
ハロー、ハロー 聴こえますか
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
そっちは何年？
What year is it over there?
正しく分かり合う手段は 一つじゃないさ
There isn't just one right way to truly understand each other.
漂う時間は何処へ行くのか
Where does this drifting time go?
さよならは いつ誰が決めるの
When, and who decides when it's 'goodbye'?
その手に触れようと願ってる 本当さ
I wish to touch your hand, truly.
永遠の夜光 君に歌う
I sing to you, eternal night light.
世界中が 君にいじわるでも
Even if the whole world is unkind to you,
思い出して 覚えていて
remember it, keep it in mind.
瞼の裏 ずっとまた 会えるからね
Behind my eyelids, we'll always meet again.
穏やかに 健やかに 枯れるブーケ
A bouquet withering peacefully and healthily,
君だって 私だって
you and I alike—
消えるのは 言葉だけ
the only things that vanish are words.
ふんわり 君を抱きしめてあげるからね
I'll gently hold you close, so
泣かないで
don't cry.
延々と続く今日は 雪原のようで
Today, stretching endlessly like a snowy field,
当然の幸せでも 眩ませるんだ
dazzles even natural happiness.
忘れないで 何処へだって繋がる回線
Don't forget the line connecting us anywhere.
寂しい宇宙とオレンジの公園
A lonely universe and an orange park.
慕わしい心の限りを 歌おう
Let's sing with all our yearning hearts.
永遠の夜光 届くよね
Eternal night light, it will reach you, right?
幻想よりも優しいかたちのまま
In a form gentler than any illusion.
濡れそぼる その頬を
Your damp cheeks
こっそり撫でて 乾かしてあげるからね
I'll secretly stroke and dry for you.
何度だって
No matter how many times—
no matter how many times—
永遠の夜光 虚空に歌う
I sing into the void, eternal night light.
会いたいよ 消えたくなんでないよ
I want to see you; I don't want to disappear at all.
思い出して 覚えていて
Remember it, keep it in mind.
今 ここで 笑い合ったことを
What we laughed about here and now.
永遠の夜光 君に歌う
I sing to you, eternal night light.
世界中が 君にいじわるでも
Even if the whole world is unkind to you,
思い出して 覚えていて
remember it, keep it in mind.
瞼の裏 ずっとまた 会えるからね
Behind my eyelids, we'll always meet again.
さよならは さよならは
Goodbyes, goodbyes—
ねえ 誰が 決めるもの
Hey, who is it that decides them?
消えるのは 言葉だけ
The only things that vanish are words.
ふんわり 君を抱きしめてあげるからね
I'll gently hold you close, so
泣かないで
don't cry.
はい、え、みんなびっくりした！新曲2曲続けてお送りしましたー！
Hi, everyone, were you surprised? We just delivered two new songs back-to-back!
1曲目は「さよならは、まだ」、そして2曲目は「夜光通信」、いかがででしたでしょうか？ どちらもめっちゃかっこよくて、うちはお気に入りです。
The first was 'Sayonara wa, Mada' and the second was 'Yakou Tsuushin'. How was it? Both are super cool, and they're my favorites.
あのね、「夜光通信」、2曲目の夜光通信なんですけど、この後MVを投稿するので、ぜひ一緒に見てほしいです。ありがとうございました！
Um, for 'Yakou Tsuushin', the second song, we're posting the MV after this, so I hope you'll watch it together. Thank you so much!
というわけでね、なんか、ちょっと、圧を感じる。
And so, um... I kind of feel some pressure.
なんか、で、めちゃくちゃでかくない？なんでこんなでかくなったんだ？
Like, why are they so huge? Why did they get so big?
ま、この2匹はちょっと、あの、あとでメンバーシップ限定の放送を、この後やる予定なので、
Well, these two will be... um, later we're planning to do a membership-exclusive broadcast after this,
メンバーシップ限定の放送のときにご紹介したいと思います。はい。
so I'd like to introduce them during the membership broadcast. Yes.
というわけで、えー、ちょっと、以上になるんだよね。寂しいんだけどさ、ちょっと、うち、みんなにお手紙書いてきたから、それを読んでもいい？ちょっと、ちょっと待っててね。
So, um... that's about it. It's lonely, but you know, I wrote a letter for everyone, so can I read it? Just wait a moment, okay?
はいというわけで、みんなにお手紙書いてきたので聞いてください。
So, I've written a letter for everyone, so please listen.
すべてのミオファ、そしてホロライブファンのみんなへ、デビューしてからの4年間あっという間でした。
To all Miofa and Hololive fans: The 4 years since my debut have flown by.
最初にデビューした時は、とにかくがむしゃらに色々模索したり、勝手に悩んで、病んだりしていました。
When I first debuted, I was rushing forward, exploring things, worrying and getting down on my own.
この4年間は本当に語りきれないぐらい、楽しいことも苦しいこともありました。
These 4 years had so much joy and hardship that I can't even put it all into words.
でも、泣いたり笑ったりしながらもホロライブを応援し続けてくれたみんな、
Yet through tears and laughter, everyone who kept supporting Hololive...
そしてうち、大神ミオを応援し続けてくれたみんながいてくれたから、4周年をこうして迎えることができたんだと心の底から思っています。
...and everyone who kept supporting me, Ookami Mio, is why I can welcome this 4th anniversary, from the bottom of my heart.
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
これから5年目をみんなと歩くことになりますが、いっぱいっぱい笑って過ごそうね！
From here on, I'll walk our 5th year with everyone, so let's spend it smiling to our hearts' content!
うちのことをみんなが愛してくれるように、うちもみんなのことを愛しています。
Just as you all love me, I love you all just as much.
5年目もよろしくね！ミオより。
Please look after our 5th year too! From Mio.
あ、ちょっと恥ずかしい。
Ah, that's a bit embarrassing.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや、すごい、みんなにはすごく感謝しているんだよ。ありがとう。
I'm really, really grateful to everyone. Thank you.
今日はちょっとヴァーチャル寂しいけど、普通の放送もぜひ見に来てください。
It's a bit lonely virtually today, but please come watch my regular streams too.
というわけで、ありがとうねみんな！
With that said, thank you everyone!
バイバイ！寂しい。バイバイ！
Bye-bye! I'll miss you. Bye-bye!
はい！グッズ紹介担当の大神ミオです！
Yes! I'm Ookami Mio, in charge of merch introduction!
パンパカパーン！4周年記念グッズが発売されます！わー！
Ta-da! The 4th anniversary merch is now on sale! Yay!
気になる内容のご紹介！まずはお馴染みパパ描き下ろし、
Introducing the items you're curious about! First, newly drawn by Izumi papa,
アクリルジオラマスタンド！
the acrylic diorama stand!
なんと昨日お披露目の新衣装グッズです！
This is our brand-new outfit merch unveiled just yesterday!
ちょっとポーズがセクシーなんだけど、ミオファがとても可愛い！
The pose is a bit sexy, but Miofa looks so cute!
そしてそして、
And then,
マグカップ！
the mug!
うちが温かいお茶をよく飲むので、あったら嬉しいなって思って作りました！みんなも、お揃いのマグでお茶のもうね！
I often drink warm tea, so I made this thinking it'd be great to have! Everyone, let's drink tea with matching mugs too!
そして、なんと待望の！
And, what's more, the long-awaited...
ミオファぬいぐるみ（かけるに）！
Miofa plushie (choose from two)!
狼の姿と猫の姿、両方同時発売です！
Both the wolf and cat versions are released at the same time!
めっちゃ可愛い！
Super cute!
クオリティ重視で作ってもらいました！
We had it made with a focus on quality!
早くおうちにきてほしいなー！
I hope they come to your homes soon!
そして、今回特典があります！まずはボイスが2つ！
And there are special bonuses this time! First, two voice packs!
みんなへの感謝の気持ちボイスと、シチュエーションボイスの2つです！
A voice expressing gratitude to everyone and a situational voice, making two in total!
ボイス録音はいつもちょっと恥ずかしいけど、ありがとうの気持ち聞いてほしいな！
Recording voices is always a bit embarrassing, but I want you to hear my feelings of gratitude!
さらに、今年も頑張ります！
Furthermore, I'll do my best this year too!
大神ミオ直筆サイン入り、複製箔押しメッセージ入りポストカード！
A postcard with a replicated foil-stamped message and Ookami Mio's authentic autograph!
こちら限定数なしで、フルセット購入の方全員にサインを書かせていただきます！1枚1枚思いを込めて書くよ！
With no limited quantity, I'll personally sign for everyone who purchases the full set! I'll write each one with all my heart!
以上グッズ紹介でした！
That concludes the merch introduction!
この後メンバーシップ限定の放送もあるのでお楽しみに！
Afterwards, there will also be a membership-limited stream, so look forward to it!
4周年記念ライブ、すっごく楽しかった！5年目も一緒に楽しい思い出いっぱいつくろうね！
The 4th anniversary live was so much fun! Let's make lots of fun memories together in our 5th year too!
ありがとう！大神ミオーン！
Thank you! Ookami Mio-n!